Again.
在上个视频中
So, in the last video,
我们的练习是
I hand you try out building
要求你自己来构建神经网络
your own neural network to classify this fashion in this dataset.
并对这个数据集中的服饰进行分类
Here is my solution like how I decided to build this.
现在说说我的构建方式
So first, building our network.
首先构建网络
So, here, I'm going to import our normal modules from PyTorch.
从 PyTorch 中导入正常的模块
So, nn and optim, so,
导入 nn 和 optim
nn is going to allow us to build our network,
nn 使我们能够构建网络
and optim is going to give us our optimizers.
optim 可以为我们提供优化器
I must going to import this functional modules, so,
我们必须导入这个函数式模块
we can use functions like ReLU and log softmax.
这样才能使用 ReLU 和 log_softmax 等函数
I decided to define my network architectures using the class.
我决定使用类定义网络架构
So, in nn.modules subclassing from this,
设为 nn.module 子类
and it's called a classifier.
称为 classifier
Then I created four different linear transformations.
然后创建四个不同的线性转换
So, in this case, it's three hidden layers and then one output layer.
即三个隐藏层和一个输出层
Our first hidden layer has 256 units.
第一个隐藏层有 256 个单元
The second hidden layer has a 128,
第二个隐藏层有 128 个单元
one after that has 64.
第三个有 64 个单元
Then our output has 10 units.
输出有 10 个单元
So, in the forward pass, I did something a little different.
在前向传播里我执行的操作有所不同
So, I made sure here that the input tensor is actually flattened.
我在这里扁平化了输入张量
So now, you don't have to flatten your input tensors in the training loop,
这样你就不用在训练循环中扁平化输入张量了
it'll just do it in the forward pass itself.
在前向传播里就会扁平化
So, to do this is do x.view,
输入 x.view
which is going to change our shape.
它将更改形状
So, x.shape zero is going to give us our batch size.
x.shape[0] 表示批次大小
Then the negative one here is going to basically fill out
这里的 -1
the the second dimension with as many elements as it
将决定第二个维度的大小
needs to keep the same total number of elements.
同时使元素总数量保持不变
So, what this does is it basically gives us another tensor,
这样会生成另一个张量
that is the flattened version of our input tensor.
它是输入张量的扁平化版本
It doing a pass these through our linear transformations,
经过这些线性转换
and then ReLU activation functions.
然后经过 ReLU 激活函数
Then finally, we use a log softmax with a dimension set to one,
最后是 log_softmax 维度设为 1
as our output, and return that from our forward function.
这就是输出 从 forward 函数中返回它
With the model defined,
定义好模型后
I can do model equals classifiers.
在这里输入 model = classifier
So, this actually creates our model.
这样就会创建模型
Then we define our criterion with the negative log likelihood loss.
然后将 criterion 设为负对数似然损失
So, I'm using log softmax as the output my model.
我将模型输入设为 log_softmax
So, I want to use the NLLLoss as the criterion.
并将 criterion 设为 NLLLoss
Then, here I'm using the Adam optimizer.
然后使用 Adam 优化器
So, this is basically the same as stochastic gradient descent,
它和随机梯度下降法基本一样
but it has some nice properties where it uses
但是具有一些优势
momentum which speeds up the actual fitting process.
它会使用动力加速拟合流程
It also adjust the learning rate for each of the individual parameters in your model.
它还会调整模型中每个参数的学习速率
Here, I wrote my training loop.
这是训练循环
So, again I'm using five epochs.
我同样使用了 5 个周期
So, for e in range epoch, so,
for e in range(epoch):
this is going to basically loop through our dataset five times,
这样会遍历数据集五次
I'm tracking the loss with running loss,
使用 running_loss 跟踪损失
and just kind of instantiated it here.
在这里初始化它
Then, getting our images.
然后获取图像
So, from images labels in train loader,
for images, labels in trainloader
so I get our log probabilities by passing in the images to a model.
通过将图像传入模型里获取对数概率
So, one thing to note, you can kind of do a little shortcut.
要注意的一点是 这里有个捷径
If you just pass these in to model as if it was a function,
如果将 model 当做函数并将图像直接传入 model 中
then it will run the forward method.
model 将运行 forward 方法
So, this is just a kind of a shorter way to run the forward pass through your model.
这是对模型进行前向传播的简便方式
Then with the log probabilities and the labels,
然后使用对数概率和标签
I can calculate the loss.
计算损失
Then here, I am zeroing the gradients.
在这里清理梯度
Now I'm doing the lost up backwards to calculating our gradients,
在这里运行 loss_backward() 以计算梯度
and then with the gradients, I can do our optimizer step.
获得梯度后 执行优化器步骤
If we tried it, we can see at least for
我们会看到
these first five epochs that are loss actually drops.
五个周期后 损失开始下降了
Now the network is trained,
训练好网络后
we can actually test it out.
我们可以测试网络
So, we pass in data to our model, calculate the probabilities.
向模型中传入数据 计算概率
So, here, doing the forward pass through the model to
在这里对模型进行前向传播
get our actual log probabilities and with the log probabilities,
获得对数概率
you can take the exponential to get the actual probabilities.
然后计算指数以获得实际概率
Then with that, we can pass it into this nice little view classify function that I wrote,
然后传入到我编写的这个 view_classify 辅助函数里
and it shows us,
可以看到
if we pass an image of a shirt,
如果我们传入衬衫图像
it tells us that it's a shirt.
它将告诉我们这是衬衫
So, our network seems to have learned fairly well,
初步看来 网络学习的效果还不错
what this dataset is showing us.
能判断出数据集里的内容是什么